King Lear is a drama, tv movie film directed by Richard Eyre.
An aging King invites disaster, when he abdicates to his corrupt,
toadying daughters, and rejects his loving and honest one.
Lear, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Goneril, played by Emma Thompson.
Regan, played by Emily Watson.
Earl of Gloucester, played by Jim Broadbent.
Cordelia, played by Florence Pugh.
Earl of Kent, played by Jim Carter.
King Lear is a 2018 British-American television film directed by Richard Eyre.
An adaptation of the play of the same name by William Shakespeare, cut to
just 115 minutes, it was broadcast on BBC Two on 28 May 2018.
Starring Anthony Hopkins as the title character, the abridged adaptation is set in a highly militarised version of 21st-century London and depicts the
tragedy that follows when the sovereign King Lear announces the end of his reign and the division of his kingdom among his three daughters.
The adaptation was met with positive reviews, which commended its acting, and
many singled out Hopkins for his performance in the title role.
The film explores themes of theater play, fool, tragedy, storm, king lear.
The tone is emotional.